# **Dhandy Joenathan Kurnia Putra**

+6285735452578 | dhanjoenkp@gmail.com | github.com/dhandvjoe | linkedin.com/in/dhandvjoenathan

#### SHORT DESCRIPTION

I am a fresh graduate who is passionate about testing software. Highly motivated technology professional launching career as a software quality engineer. Knowledge about basic programming and object oriented programming. Recently I joined Quality Engineer Bootcamp in Alterra Academy to improve my hard skills and soft skills. I learned a lot of things in this bootcamp, starting with creating test plans until now I am skilled using automation framework (Selenium, Appium, Rest Assured, JMeter, etc).

#### **SKILL SET**

- Tools: Java, Kotlin, Python, HTML & CSS, PHP, MySQL, Git, Github, Linux
- Software Testing: Visual Studio Code, Intellij IDEA, Postman, Android Studio, MySQL Workbench
- Framework Testing: Selenium, Appium, Rest Assured, JMeter, Serenity BDD, Cucumber

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Quality Assurance**

PT KB Finansia Multi Finance - KreditPlus

Sept 2022 - Present

## **Quality Assurance Intern**

PT. Samala Serasi Unggul - Rumah Siap Kerja

July 2022 - Sept 2022

- Assisting team to test and review new features before product launch
- Create and conduct proper testing report
- Collaborate with QA team to plan and execute testing

## **Software Engineer Intern**

Imperial Healthtech

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

- Contribute to developing a web or mobile application using Flutter.
- Create a unit test to test certain features.
- Daily standup for work progress every day with the team.

## Android Developer - Independent Study by Kampus Merdeka

Dicoding Indonesia

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

- Do starting class from basic programming, git, until android jetpack pro
- Work on Android app projects using the Kotlin language.
- Participate in hard-skill and soft-skill class activities.
- Developing a 'Stockku' application from the results of the Independent Study program.

#### **Lecturer Assistant**

Oracle Database Administration

Apr 2021 - Jul 2021

- Teach the basic designing a database, best practice design a database with ERD (Entity Relationship Diagram).
- Teach how to create tablespace until backup and recovery database.

Object-oriented Programming (OOP)

Apr 2020 - Aug 2020

- Explain a little bit about basic programming using Java, such as variables, data type, looping, condition, and many more.
- Teach how to implement OOP.

# **PROJECT**

LesGoo

Website : <u>les-goo.vercel.app</u>

Aug 2022

Quality Engineer (Manual & Automation - API / Website Testing)

- Create test plan, scenario program for testing application
- Manual testing API / Website using Postman / Chrome

- Automation API testing with Rest Assured framework and Serenity BDD
- Automation Web testing with Selenium Java framework and Serenity BDD

#### Sauce Demo

Github: github.com/dhandyjoe/SeleniumCucumber-SauceDemo

Quality Engineer (Automation Website using Selenium Framework)

- Create test plan, scenario program for testing application
- Automation function test with Selenium framework and Serenity BDD

## **Simple Calculator**

Github: github.com/dhandyjoe/Appium-SimpleCalculatorApp

Quality Engineer (Automation Mobile using Appium Framework)

- Create test plan, scenario program for testing application
- Automation function test with Appium framework and Serenity BDD

#### Stockku

Github: github.com/dhandyjoe/dicoding.stockku.capstone

Android Developer

- Design a database for a land book register application with MySQL;
- Design and create user interfaces for land book register app with Bootstrap;
- Create a land book register with Laravel Framework;
- Create PDF Export & Print Feature with DOMPdf;
- Deploy the application to local servers and officers can access the app using local wifi connection.

## **EDUCATION**

## Alterra Academy

Immersive Program - Quality Engineer Bootcamp

May 2022 - Aug 2022

## Satya Wacana Christian University

Bachelor of Computer Science (Information System)

GPA: 3.9/4.0

Aug 2018 - Oct 2022

Sep 2020 - May 2021

# **ORGANIZATION**

# • ISFest - Information System Festival

Head of Funding Section Committee

- ISFest is a creative idea competition where participants must have ideas about "Smart City".
- Do fundraising to meet the specified fund target.
- Make a budget plan for all the events that have been planned.

## **ADDITIONAL**

Languages Interest : Bahasa Indonesia (Proficient) and English (Intermediate)

: Music Instrument (Keyboard & Guitar), Music Arrangement

Sep 2022

Sep 2022

Apr 2022